Culfin Projects Limited Patrick Gibbons

Bury Greater Manchester Mobile: 07722153479

Email: sitemanagement.gibbons@gmail.com

Personal Statement

I am a Site Manager with 19 years' experience in the construction industry

Due to my tradesman background and my passion for maths and sciences I consider myself a technical minded person. I enjoy working in a hands-on type role.

I'm continually enrolling on training courses to further advance my skills set

I enjoy researching and developing new concepts on how I can improve company procedures to increase health and safety awareness throughout my sites.

I pay great attention to detail which I demonstrate effectively by using various methods to maintain quality standards.

I work well with others to ensure we all reach personal and project goals.

I am trustworthy and honest, extremely hard working and very dedicated to my career and to that of my clients. I can problem solve well and have excellent communication skills. I can present my findings and information to clients in a non-technical manner to ensure they understand.

I'm willing to travel nationwide

Education

Sept 1992 – July 1997 St Gabriel's Roman Catholic High School GCSE's 8 Grades B-D Sept 1997 – July 2000 Bolton College NVQ's Level 1, 2, and 3 - Carpentry and Joinery NVQ's Level 1, 2 – Wood Machining

Licenses

Feb 1998

Full Clean UK Drivers Licence

Site Management experience in the following sectors

1st & 2nd fix

Civil Engineering Finishing Joinery

Government Funded Projects

Ground work

Hotels & Restaurants

Airport works
Prison works

Mechanical & Electrical (M&E)

New Build Housing
Plumbing and Heating
PV Solar / Renewable Energy

Refrigeration Phasing

Refurbishments - Supermarkets Residential Refurbishment)

Air Conditioning Fire Stopping Flooring Tiling

Steel Frame Structures

Industrial Roofing (Inc. Metal Cladding)

Sewer Diversions

Piling Acoustic Engineering

Qualifications & Licenses

NVQ Level 6 Site Management Diploma

Date Achieved: July 2016

CITB Managers and Professionals -

Date achieved: July 2016

CSCS Black Card – Date achieved: Sept 2016

MS office 365 – Ongoing

SMSTS Course - Updated 2019

3 Day First Aid Course-Oct 2018 – Oct 2021 **Fire Marshall Certificate** – Updated Jan 2019 **Working at Heights Certificate** – Updated Jan

2019

UKATA - Asbestos Awareness — Updated 2019 PV Solar Installations Certificate — Jan 2012

Communication, Record keeping &

Confidentiality - Date achieved: Nov 2006

Microsoft Word Advanced Certificate -

Date achieved: Sept 2016

MicrosoftExcel Advanced Certificate -

Date achieved: Sept 2016

Microsoft PowerPoint Certificate Advanced -

Date achieved: Sept 2016

TESCO – Site Safety Standards - Oct 2016 – Oct 2017

TESCO – Development in Trading Stores

Oct 2016 - Oct 2017

IPAF Licences (Categories 1b, 3a and 3b) -

12 Dec 2016 – 31 Dec 2021

SPA PASSPORT (Petroleum Stations) – Dec

2016 – Dec 2019

PASMA (Mobile Tower Scaffold Erecting) - Dec

2016 - Dec 2021

FLT (Counter Balance) – Sept 2017 – Sept 2020

Employment History

Jan 2019 – March 2019 Sharkey Construction Ltd

Working on an extremely fast pace maintenance contract on Tesco Extra in Middleton, Greater Manchester. Working in a live environment I was overseeing the completion of works on night shifts. I worked back to back shifts without a break to maximise getting the work completed in the tight time frame given.

March 2018 - January 2019 MALT Projects Ltd

I was taken on to convert an old 3 storey British Home Stores Building into three separate units. The Building is situated in the middle of Warrington's Golden Square Shopping Centre.

Unit 1 (Basement Level) - Bistro café

Unit 2 (Ground floor, Shopping Mall) – Wilkinson's Store

Unit 3 (First Floor Level) - SuperBowl

I took the project from Cradle to Grave. I organised the pre-start meeting and prepared for the Pre-Construction Health & Safety Plan and updated it throughout the project, held fortnightly progress meetings and prepared the reports. Organised contractors and resources for site.

Created procurement lists on Microsoft Excel and arranged delivery schedules for plant and equipment to be delivered and installed.

I put together the programme on Microsoft Project, distributed it to all contractors involved in delivering the project

I designed all the health and safety permits & checklists for site.

Completed O+M Manuals for each unit.

Due to the age of the building, there was a lot of structural issues which needed to be overcome. There was a lot of supporting steel work which needed to be installed.

Due to the nature of the Unit 3 being converted into a bowling alley there was a lot of unique elements involved in the design and layout of the unit to sound deaden the unit to achieve acoustic readings which would be satisfactory to surrounding businesses within the shopping centre

From a health and safety perspective, there was a lot to consider in managing and maintaining site safety at key stages of the project. Especially when overseeing the construction of a new roof, asbestos removal throughout the building and elevators and escalators being installed

My role was diverse and demanding. I was performing a dual role, being both site manager and project manager.

Estimated value of project: 4 Million Pounds

November 2017 - December 2017 Winvic

Working on a 150 million pound project in Westhoughton, Bolton, for the client Amazon.

Due to my experience overseeing the mechanical installation of steel work, conveyors and hi-tech scanning machines, I was taken on by Winvic to supervise the following European contractors: Vanderlande, Fischer and Hormacher.

My main duties were to ensure the installation work was carried out with a strong focus on Health & Safety.

This work was carried out on night shifts. Throughout the night, I carried out sound monitoring tests and gathered vital information which I documented in my handover diary, for the managers following on from my night shift in the morning.

September 2107 – November 2017 Vanderlande Industries

Working for one of the world's largest baggage Handling company. I was taken on to manage the construction and civils package at Manchester Airport Terminal 1

The project was to remove an existing scanner and conveyor system to allow for the installation of a the new CTX 9800 scanner and conveyors.

Due to a lack of pre-construction information, a lot of investigation work was necessary and liaising with structural engineers to gather missing information to allow for the successful installation of the machine.

I was responsible for managing the overall project. Due to the strict security measures at the airport, I had to build very strong communication routes with various departments within the Manchester Airport Group to ensure all processes were integrated into the construction work to deliver each phase successfully.

January 2017 – September 2017 Braithwaite Fit

Since January this year, I have been a managing a project for Lidl in Blackpool. My role was to manage the project, every step of the way from designing the programme, organising contractors & fortnightly progress meetings to overseeing health and Safety on site, to liaising with the architects and structural engineers to ensure variations and issues were resolved promptly and drawings were revised and approved by the client. The project consisted of 3 main phases:

Phase 1 – Sewer Diversion, moving the sewer in the customer car park away from supermarket to allow for the proposed extension to be built. The diversion was approximately 80 meters long. It took place while the store was still trading and using sections of the car park. The diversion needed to be piled due to poor ground conditions and specialised equipment and contractors were used, along with liaising with various professionals and governments to ensure H&S and Building and Highway Regulations were met at every stage of construction

Phase 2 – Building the extension, the supermarket received an "L" Shape extension. This new area created a Nische Bakery and an extra aisle for shoppers

Phase 3 – Once, the extension was built and watertight. The store closed for 5.5 weeks for a full refurbishment. This included fitting a new sprinkler system throughout the store to adhere to current regulations

September 2016 – December 2016 Uplands Retail

I've recently completed a £4 million-pound re-fresh project on a Tesco Extra Store in Shrewsbury, Shropshire

I'm managing a site team which includes tradesmen and subcontractors to ensure the works are carried out to programme and budget.

Monitoring Health and Safety on site

Attending progress and client meetings.

Liaising with the store management to co-ordinate work, to cause minimal disruption to the store's production

Reading and understanding drawings, specifications, preliminaries and contract documentation Requisition of materials and deliveries

Liaising with the design team to maintain high quality standards

May 2016 – Sept 2016 HB Projects

I've recently completed a 12-week refresh project on a Morrisons Store in Heywood, Greater Manchester

Constant challenges presented themselves daily while working in a trading store – working closely with my senior management team and appointed sub-contractors, I've implemented strategies to overcome obstacles to ensure each phase of the project was delivered on time and within budget

The store underwent demolition of certain areas – relocating certain trade sections to comply with the stores newly proposed layout while concessions were added to other areas. The car park had subsidence issues, this was also dealt with during the 12 weeks' project and continual updates to the road traffic plans were required

February 2014 – May 2016 CTM Management

I was working as a Site Manager overseeing multi-million-pound projects, carrying out 20 year upgrades on Aldi supermarkets throughout the North of England

I have completed 8 stores which include:

Aldi Bolton

Aldi Trafford

Aldi Bury

Aldi Horwich

Aldi Pontefract

• Aldi Rochdale

Aldi Eccles

Aldi Fenton

The above stores were all fully operational and open to the public during the day so it was vital that all trades worked productively with health and safety as a priority. Extra care was taken to ensure that the store was always safe for not just the various trades but also for the staff and customers who occupied it daily. Handover sheets were completed daily to ensure the store management were fully satisfied with how the store was returned to them after work had been completed.

Duties included: Inductions, enforcing Health & Safety procedures were followed, trades worked strictly to their specific Risk Assessments and Method Statements, Tool Box talks, setting up Site, Reading & understanding architectural drawings and liaising with the Aldi management team, Quantity Surveyors, Architects and other professional to ensure the design quality standards were met, while maintaining the programme stayed on schedule and all work was carried out safely, within budget and without concern.

September 2012 – February 2014 Kingspan Energy / Sainsbury's

Working as a Project Manager / Consultant I was in charge of multi-million pound projects. I looked after the UK contracts for Sainsbury's supermarket chain

Some of the flag ship stores I've listed below:

- Sainsbury's Distribution Warehouse Thameside, London
- Sainsbury's Ilford, London
- Sainsbury's Brookwood, Guildford

- Sainsbury's Heaton Park, Manchester
- Sainsbury's Stockport

I was responsible for the safety of all Mechanical and Electrical Engineers and other trades on site along with all customers shopping and Sainsbury's staff working in store.

Some of my main duties include: - Site set up, creating Road Traffic / Waste Management Plans, Fire escape routes, site inductions, Assessing RAMS, Tool Box Talks and liaising with Store Managers to resolve pending issues ensuring the project stays on track & have minimal disruption on the daily running of each active store.

July 2010 – September 2012 Stonewood Building Services

Employed as a site manager I was responsible for the initial site set up and day to day running of projects which involved refurbishing government funded properties for disability access.

- Manage requisition and delivery of materials
- Liaising with subcontractors, issuing short term programmes and monitoring their works
- Holding regular progress meetings
- Ensure programme deadlines are met
- Ensure correct quantity and quality of labour is available on site with the correct PPE and certification
- Attending monthly cost meetings
- Ensure full compliance of all H&S Policy and procedures, obtain relevant Risk Assessments and Method Statements from all trades starting work on site

November 2009 – July 2010 Manley Construction Limited – Site Manager / Project Manager

I managed government funded projects for Preston City Council varying from social housing, Universities and other types of projects, my responsibilities included;

- Monitoring multiple sites daily in terms of health and safety, quality and progress.
- Coordinating and delegating works with other trades and in-house operatives.
- Tool box talks
- Auditing RAMS
- Liaising with professionals to resolve structural issues
- Responsible for interviewing and hiring Contractors and Subcontractors

January 2009 – November 2009 HMP Styal Prison Service, Manchester – Foreman Joiner

Working as part of the Prison Works Department I was responsible for organising the operations involved in building and maintaining the prison

- Organising Staff rota
- Enforcing security procedures
- Working towards company set targets while staying within budget
- Implementing Security checks and Audits
- Disciplinary procedures
- Costing
- Heading meeting with the Stakeholders and other professionals

January 2008 – December 2008 Various Recruitment Agencies - Site Manager

Working as a Site Manager/Working Joiner (Foreman) estimated value of projects between 1 and 5 million pound. Some of the projects I've listed below;

- Student accommodation in Manchester
- Student University in Manchester Stockford Building
- Preston University
- Blackburn University
- Marks & Spencer's Market Street, Manchester
- Hope Hospital,
- Tesco Padiham Superstore
- Manchester University

October 2007 – January 2008 Unidata Infrastructure - PV solar Installations Operations Manager

Working as an Operations Manager for a Southern based company called Unidata.

I oversaw several teams of solar panel installers within the Blackburn and Preston Area

Working with Preston, Blackburn and Darwen Council on housing Association properties overseeing the installation of Solar Panels on the roofs of tenants who were eligible for government grants

- Ordering materials
- Vetting staff
- Company costing
- Enforcing Health and safety Procedures
- Providing Welfare Facilities
- Liaising with Council representatives and other blue/white collar professionals
- Resolving tenant issues
- Tool box talks

Jan 2005 – Oct 2007 Stonewood Building Services – Project Manager

In charge of the complete building of residential properties for a Northwest building firm

Other responsibilities include:

- Liaising with clients and reporting progress, professional staff (such as architects and surveyors) and the public
- Supervising contracted staff
- Meeting subcontractors
- Making safety inspections and ensuring construction and site safety
- Checking and preparing site reports, designs and drawings
- Maintaining quality control procedures
- Motivating the workforce
- Problem solving
- Using specialist construction management computer applications
- Civil engineering companies
- Building companies
- Construction companies and contractors

Jul 2004 – Jan 2005 Agency Joiner/General Building

Multi-skilled work including joinery, plastering, tiling, plumbing and painting, working for various contractors throughout the North-West area mainly on New Builds and Refurbishment sites including

White Rose – Shop fitting
Everest – Window fitting
Rochdale Housing Association - Various
Cruden – Kitchen fitting

Jun 2001 - Jul 2004 Alfa Kitchens - Joiner

Provided with a company van, supplying all my own tools, fitting kitchens in various domestic and commercial properties

Sept 1997 - Jun 2003 MK Wilson Maintenance – Apprentice Joiner

Working as an apprentice joiner and achieved NVQ Level 3 Joinery, learning all aspects of joinery and general building including health and safety responsibilities on site.

Hobbies and interest

Keeping Fit - I attend a gym and enjoy hiking, I've recently completed the 3-peak challenge **Visiting Historical places** – I recently travelled to Auschwitz in Poland to visit the prisoner of war camp **Reading and watching documentaries** – Learning about different time periods of the world, civilisations and cultures

Charity events – I attend charity events to show support and help raise money by running. I've taken part in the Bupa London 10k run for Samantha Dickson Brain Tumour Trust

Socialising – Cooking for friends and dining out

Language Study – Learning German

Certificates, Qualifications and References are available upon request